https://www.riai.ie/terms-of-use

Home
Work with an Architect
What Does an Architect Do?
Find an Architect
Search for an architectural practice by name, by area, or by specialism
RIAI Jobsearch
Why Choose a Career in Architecture?
RIAI Student Awards
RIAI Scott Tallon Walker Student Excellence Award in Architecture
Old House New Home
An RIAI online guide on how to understand, reimagine and conserve your historic house
Registering as an Architect
Why must Architects Register?
Register as an Architect
Find out everything you need to know about registering as an Architect in Ireland
Also of interest
Brexit FAQs: Recognition of UK qualified Architects in Ireland in the case of a no-deal Brexit
Introduction
This page sets out terms of use for the website www.riai.ie.
The terms of use are set out in three sections: Legal Disclaimer; Privacy Statement; Cookie Policy.
Legal Disclaimer
The Royal Institute of the Architects of Ireland (RIAI) is charged with various regulatory responsibilities under the Building Control Act 2007 in relation in the admission and professional conduct of architects and therefore cannot provide specific advice in relation to particular facts concerning complaints against architects. There are designated statutory bodies namely, the Professional Conduct Committee, the Appeals Body and the Registrar who have a role in relation to such matters. Accordingly, the Royal Institute of the Architects of Ireland is limited to assisting you in relation to your access to the services offered by these bodies.  Nothing said by or on behalf of the Royal Institute of the Architects of Ireland in doing so is to be taken as advice.
The RIAI is registered in Ireland.
Company Registration Number: 003498.
Company Registered Address: 8 Merrion Square, Dublin 2
The information contained in this Site is for general guidance on matters of interest only. The application and impact of laws can vary widely based on the specific facts involved. Given the changing nature of construction laws, rules and regulations, and the inherent hazards of electronic communication, there may be delays, omissions or inaccuracies in information contained in this Site.
Accordingly, the information on this Site is provided with the understanding that the authors and publishers are not herein engaged in rendering professional advice and services. As such, it should not be used as a substitute for consultation with competent professional advisers. Before making any decision or taking any action, you should consult a RIAI staff member.
While we have made every attempt to ensure that the information contained in this Site has been obtained from reliable sources, the RIAI is not responsible for any errors or omissions, or for the results obtained from the use of this information. All information in this Site is provided "as is", with no guarantee of completeness, accuracy, timeliness or of the results obtained from the use of this information, and without warranty of any kind, express or implied, including, but not limited to warranties of performance, merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose.
In no event will the RIAI, its related partnerships or corporations, or the partners, agents or employees thereof be liable to you or anyone else for any decision made or action taken in reliance on the information in this Site or for any consequential, special or similar damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
Certain links in this Site connect to other Web Sites maintained by third parties over whom the RIAI has no control. The RIAI makes no representations as to the accuracy of information contained in other Web Sites.
Privacy Statement
Introduction
The Royal Institute of the Architects of Ireland (the “RIAI”, “we”, “us”, “our”) is a Data Controller for personal information provided by you. We will use this information subject to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and any applicable data protection legislation in Ireland and the E.U (“Applicable Data Protection legislation”). We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our members, registrants and members of the public. We have created this Privacy Statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of your information and to explain to you our use of your information.
The RIAI website (our “Website”) is operated by the RIAI (“we”, “us”, “our”, “RIAI”).  In order to fully understand your rights, we encourage you to read this Privacy Statement before continuing to use our Website. If you have any queries in relation to our use of your information you may contact dataprotection@riai.ie.
Information we may collect from you
We collect the following information:
Information that you provide to us when using our Website. This includes information provided at the time of logging in to use our Website.
Information you provide to us when signing up to receiving the RIAI Public Newsletter, which will typically include your name and email address.
If you contact us for any reason, we may keep a record of that correspondence for as long as it is necessary regarding the nature of your contact.
Details of your visits to our Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data and other communication data and the resources, advertisements and linked sites that you access.
Information such as name and photographs at RIAI events.
Our Website uses cookies. The purpose of the cookies is solely to assist us in redesigning our Website to ensure we provide relevant information in an easily accessible format. Please click here for our Cookie Policy.
The search facility on our Website is an internal search function and returns only information that appears on our Website.
How we use your information
We may use your personal information for the purposes of:
Administering our website;
Allowing us to perform our functions and objectives as set out in the Building Control Act 2007 and our Constitution;
Enabling your access to and use of the Website services;
To ensure that content from our Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
To provide you with information that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes or where it is within the performance of the functions of the RIAI to provide you with this information;
To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;
To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Website;
To notify you about changes to our Website and/or services.
Legal basis
We collect and use your personal information on one or more of the following grounds:
You have given your consent;
It is necessary to fulfil our contract with you;
It is necessary and proportionate for the performance of our functions under the Building Control Act 2007 and as set out in our Constitution; namely but not limited to, supporting, regulating and promoting the practice of architecture in Ireland;
We may also use your information to promote the need for research and development in architecture, conservation, construction, urban design, the built environment and associated arts and sciences and to provide you with information which may be of interest to you (e.g. CPD Courses, publications) and we may contact you about these by post and telephone. You are free to unsubscribe and opt-out of this communication at any time and we will always provide you with a way of doing so.
Disclosure of your information
In certain circumstances we may disclose your personal information to data processers working directly on our behalf. In all instances we will ensure that your information is given the appropriate level of data protection under the Applicable Data Protection Legislation and that such data processors are subject to a contractual arrangement ensuring that your information is protected.
Storage of your information
In certain cases we may transfer your personal information to recipients outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”)
We only transfer your information to recipients outside the EEA when it is necessary for the services we provide you, or subject to safeguards that assure the protection of your information.
Where we transfer your information we do so in accordance with Applicable Data Protection Legislation. We may rely on different legal mechanism to ensure the transfer is lawful. If the recipient is in a country that is not deemed ‘adequate’ by the European Commission we may rely on ‘standard contractual clauses’ with the recipient. These clauses contain standard commitments approved by the EU Commission to protect the privacy and security of your information.
If the recipient is in the United States, we may alternatively rely on EU-US Privacy Shield whereby recipients are certified under the Privacy Shield Programme to receive your information.
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. We will only store your information for as long as is necessary given the purpose for which it was gathered.
Your rights
If you would like to request access to your personal information or ask that we amend your information or seek an erasure of your information please do so by emailing  dataprotection@riai.ie.
If you have consented to the use of your personal information you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.
We hope you are happy with how we use your information but if you are not you may lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Commissioner at info@dataprotection.ie.
Cookie Policy
Introduction
This Cookie Policy describes the different types of cookies and similar technologies that may be applied on the Royal Institute of the Architects of Ireland site.
The Royal Institute of the Architects of Ireland may change this Cookie Policy at any time. Any changes in this Cookie Policy will become effective when we make the revised Cookie Policy available on or through the site.
What is a Cookie?
A cookie is a small text file which is sent to your computer or mobile device by the web server so that a website can remember some information about your browsing activity on the website. The cookie will collect information relating to your use of our sites, information about your device such as the device’s IP address and browser type, demographic data and, if you arrived at our site via a link from third party site, the URL of the linking page.
If you are a registered user or subscriber it may also collect your name and email address, which may be transferred to data processors for registered user or subscriber verification purposes.
Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently remembering your preferences, and generally improving your website experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.
Most sites you visit will use cookies in order to improve your user experience by enabling that site to ‘remember’ you, either for the duration of your visit (using a ‘session cookie’) or for repeat visits (using a ‘persistent cookie’).
A persistent cookie can remain on your computer for a pre-defined period of time, or until they are forcibly deleted. Other technologies including pixels, tags, web beacons or local storage also store and retrieve data on a device and are similar to cookies.
Cookies Used on this Site
The RIAI uses cookies in order to make this site easier to use, to support the provision of information and functionality to you, as well as to provide us with information about how this site is used so that we can make sure it is as up to date, relevant and error free as we can.
Further information about the types of cookies that are used on this site is set out below.
Please be aware that some functionality on our websites requires the use of cookies, and as such, disabling these may result in a deterioration of service. Doing so may also affect our ability to update this site to cater for user preferences and improve its performance.
Strictly Necessary Cookies
Strictly necessary cookies are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website. Without these absolutely necessary cookies, the site will not perform as smoothly for you as we would like it to and we may not be able to provide the Site with certain services or features.
Cookie Name
Description
Expiry Date
1st Party or 3rd Party
Di2
Tracks cookie expiration
12/11/2018
1st Party
Analytical Performance Cookies
Performance cookies collect information about how visitors use a site; for instance, which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies do not collect any information that identifies a visitor. The information that these cookies collect is aggregated and is therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a site works.
Cookie Name
Description
Expiry Date
1st Party or 3rd Party
_utma
Tracking traffic
After 2 years
Third party cookie
Advertising Cookies
Advertising cookies are linked to services provided by third parties. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Facebook, these third-party service providers may set their own cookies on your device. The RIAI does not control the use of these third-party cookies and cannot access them due to the way that cookies work, as cookies can only be accessed by the party who originally set them.
Cookie Name
Description
Expiry Date
1st Party or 3rd Party
_atuvc
Social media
26/05/2019
3rd party
Managing Cookies in your Browser
Some people find the idea of a website storing information on their device a little intrusive, in particular when the information is stored and used by a third party. In some cases, you can choose to accept cookies from the primary site, but block them from third parties. In others, you can block cookies from specific advertisers, or clear out all cookies. Information about the procedure to follow in order to enable or disable cookies can be found on your Internet browser provider’s site via your help screen.
(Last Updated 24/05/2018)
